American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - American Philosophical Society to Joseph Roberts, April 17, 1829; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S.: J. K. Kane, Secretary. Notice of election of Joseph Roberts to membership in the A.P.S.
  - Report on the committee on the paper by John Dawson., 1829 April 17; American Philosophical Society.
    Report of the Committee on John Dawson's Paper on the Reciprocals of Natural Numbers, which been in manuscript form for over forty years. They were sure that in the meantime the subject had been treated by some eminent mathematicians. Consequently, they did not recommend its publication in the Transactions.
  - Report of committee on Lea's paper on the genus Unio, April 17, 1829; 6x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Eglesfeld Griffith and C.Pickering. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.591.
  - Report of committee on article by John Dawson, April 17, 1829; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: F. Nichols. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.591. On same sheet is letter to E.Nulty; March 30, 1829.
  - Sam[ue]l Hazard to the Amer[ican] Philosophical Society, April 17, 1829; 8" x 10"; Hazard, Samuel, 1784-1870
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Register of Pennsylvania, II. Requests permission to use manuscripts belonging to the Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 26, 1829; 10x8; Gomez, J. M.
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. In Spanish. Concerning the analysis of a steamboat.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, secretary of the A.P.S., April 30, 1829; 7 3/4" x 12 1/4"; Hyde de Neuville, Jean Guillaume, baron, 1776-1857
    Paris, L.S. 1p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Lea's paper, May 1, 1829; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. S.: R. Eglesfeld Griffith and C. Pickering, 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.592.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 8, 1829; 8x5; Royal Astronomical Society
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W.S.Stratford. 1p.and add.,and end. Thanks for publication.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, May 18, 1829; 8" x 9 7/8"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has "some few books yet to send" to the A.P.S. Intends going to London soon.
  - Letter to the president of the scientific and literary society of Madras, May 19, 1829; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Letterpress copy of A.L.S.: Jn.Vaughan. 1p. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 22, 1829; 10x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 22, 1829; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, May 27, 1829; 9x7; Royal Irish Academy
    Dublin, L.S.: W.Bentham. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.from the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 30, 1829; 10x8; Swift, J. G. (Joseph Gardner), 1783-1865
    Philadelphia, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and add. Enc.wanting. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 2, no. 58.) Sends account of education.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1, 1829; 7-1/2x5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S.with initials. 1p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 2, no. 59.) Concerning Swift's memoir on education.
  - Letter to the Society of Friends, Philadelphia, June 10, 1829; 12-1/2x8; Crivelli, M.
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. In French. Enc. wanting. (see Ms. Comm. to the APS. Medicine, anatomy and physiology, no. 52.) Forwards his memoir on domestic economy Cf. Minutes, p.593.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, June 23 and 25, 1829; 8 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    London, 4 pp. A.L.S. Instructs Vaughan to have Dr. [Thomas] Horsfield elected to the A.P.S. London book news.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 26, 1829; 9x7-1/2; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Trinity College, Cambridge, L.S.: G. Peacock. 1p. and add., end. Thanks for APS publications. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, June 26, 1829; 9x7; Society of Antiquaries of London
    London, L.S.: Nich[olas] Carlisle. 1p., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 9, 1829; 10x8; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to P.S. Duponceau, July 14, 1829; 8" x 10"; Hays, Isaac, 1796-1879
    Phila., L.S. 3p. and end. Transmits resolutions passed by the Franklin institute on the removal of Thomas P. Jones from office of superintendent of the U.S. Patent office.
  - F[rancis] Nichols to the President of the A.P.S., July 17, 1829; 6 3/4" x 8 5/8"; Nichols, F. (Francis), fl. 1795-1820
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Suggesting a change in the procedure at the meetings of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 23, 1829; 9x7; London Institution
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wm.Maltby. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, July 25, 1829; 10x8; Santarém, Manuel Francisco de Barros e Sousa, Visconde de, 1791-1856
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Offers the APS the introduction to his Tableau Elementaire... Cf. Minutes, p.584.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, July 27, 1829; 8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Books presented to A.P.S. in the name of James Brown, purchased by Mr. Ord.
  - Geo[rge] B. Wood to Jno. K. Kane, July 30, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 5/16"; Wood, George B. (George Bacon), 1797-1879
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 4, 1829; 7-1/2x5; Robertson,
    A.L. in 3rd.P. 1p. and add., end. Donates volumes.
  - Letter to Peter [S.] DuPonceau, Aug. 7 [6], 1829; 10x8; Goetze, Peter Otto von, b. 1793
    St. Petersburg, L. 2p.and end. Copy. In Latin. Forwards publications of the imperial academy of St. Petersburg.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., 1829 August 7/19; Saint Petersbourg academie imperiale des sciences.
    The note acknowledges receipt by the Academie Imperiale des Sciences de St. Petersbourg of the 1st and 3rd volumes of the Transactions, of the Old Series.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Aug. 20, 1829; 9-1/2x8; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Rotterdam, L.S.: D. W. Dienau; J. B. Ochencan. 1p. and end. In Dutch. Forwards volume.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., August 27, 1829; 7 7/8" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. With regard to books purchased for the A.P.S. Statement of account.
  - Josiah Quincy to John K. Kane, September 1, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Quincy, Josiah
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Cambridge, Mass., 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of committee on John Gummere's paper on the projection of eclipses, Sept. 11, 1829; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Eugenius Nulty, Saml. Moore and Robert Adrian. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.595. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 467 ff.
  - Henry S. Tanner to the President of the A.P.S., September 18, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Donates a copy of his new map of United States to A.P.S. See Minutes, September 18, 1829, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 595. FILM 403 FRAME 25
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Sept. 22, 1829; 13x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, L. 1p. Extract. Meterological instrument data. On same sheet is extract of letter from Wm.Vaughan to J.Vaughan; Oct. 6, 1829.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 27, 1829; 12x8; Netherlands. Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    Gravenhage, L.S.: D.J. Van Ewyct. 2p.,end. In Dutch. ----Translation. 1p. Thanks for publication. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 30, 1829; 6-1/2x4; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards volume.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Oct. 6, 1829; 13x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    L. 1p. Extract. Meterological instrument data. On same sheet as letter from W.Vaughan to J.Vaughan; Sept. 22, 1829.
  - P. Pedersen to John Vaughan, October 7, 1829; 7 11/16" x 11 3/4"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Librarian to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 2 pp. A.L.S. Presents several books to the A.P.S. in the name of Professor [C. C.] Rafn, of Copenhagen. Titles listed.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for purchase of oil, Oct. 8, Jan. 4, 1829-1830; 4x7-1/2; Barnes, Thomas
    Philadelphia, D. 1p.and end.
  - Henry S. Tanner to Franklin Bache, October 19, 1829; 7 11/16" x 9 5/8"; Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society. FILM 403 FRAME23
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 22, 1829; 9-1/2x8; Davis, John, 1761-1847
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Donates publications.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, Oct. 24, 1829; 7-3/4x9-3/4; Quadrado y de Roó, Francisco de Paula
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and end. ----In French. 1p. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf.Minutes, p.597.
  - John M. Butten to J. P[eter] Lesley, November 2, 1829; 6 1/2" x 8"; Butten, John M.
    ----, 1 p. A.L.S. Estimate on price of engraving eight drawings.
  - Report of committee on enlarging the meeting room, Nov. 6, 1829; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Jos. Hopkinson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.597.
  - Dan[ie]l B. Smith to Franklin Bache, November 6, 1829; 6 5/8" x 8 1/8"; Smith, Daniel B., 1792-1883
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 13, 1829; 10x8; Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Donates publications.
  - Letter to [American philosophical society Paris, Nov. 16, 1829; 8" x 10"; Abrahamson, J. N. B. v. (Joseph Nicolai Benjamin)
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership; sends some of his works.
  - Levett Harris to John Vaughan, November 19, 1829; 8" x 10"; Harris, Levett
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: an Armenian grammar and a Christian prayer in Armenian text, with twenty-three different translations thereof.
  - Charles Christian Rafn to Peter Stephen DuPonceau, President of the A.P.S., November 19, 1829; 8 1/2" x 10 3/16"; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 20, 1829; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: H. H.Wilson. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Thomas Say to John Vaughan, November 20, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S. Presents his essay on shells.
  - Caleb Atwater to John Vaughan, November 26, 1829; 7 13/16" x 12 3/4"; Atwater, Caleb, 1778-1867
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. His pleasure in visiting the city of Philadelphia. Gratitude to members of the American Philosophical Society.
  - Erasmus Rask to John K. Kane, Secretary to the A.P.S., November 27, 1829; 8" x 10 1/8"; Rask, Rasmus, 1787-1832
    Copenhagen, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Philip Tidyman to John Vaughan, December 15, 1829; 7 5/8" x 9 5/16"; Tidyman, Philip
    Charleston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: the Works of Lord Bacon, in ten volumes.
  - R. Rask to John K. Kane, Secretary of A.P.S., December 16, 1829; 8 5/8" x 10 1/8"; Rask, Rasmus, 1787-1832
    Copenhagen, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to a system of expressing Arabic in European characters. Sends some papers to the A.P.S.
  - British and Foreign Bible Society to John Vaughan, December 26, 1829; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; British and Foreign Bible Society
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S.: John Jackson, Secretary. Presents to the A.P.S.: a number of versions of the sacred scriptures in some of the Oriental languages. List enclosed.
  - G. Long to John Vaughan, December 26, 1829; 8" x 9 3/4"; Long, G.
    Secretary of the A.P.S., University of London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Is sending a "small book" to the A.P.S. Remarks upon the library and the student body of the University of London.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 28, 1829; 10x8; University of Pennsylvania
    L.S.: James C. Biddle. 1p. and add., end. Donates publications.
  - Geology of the route of the Chesapeake & Delaware canal:, , 1829; 7 1/4" x 11 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    being the report of a committee...appointed to examine certain documents & geological specimens..presented by Mr. Andrew Alfred Dexter...[1829]. D. 12p. Mutilated. Committee was composed of S.G. Morton, Charles Pickering, and Jno. Wetherill. Cf. APS Minutes, July 17, Aug. 21,1829; Feb. 21, 1834. Presented by the Free Library of Philadelphia, July 1946.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 6, 1830; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Forwards volumes.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1830; 10x8; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards material.
  - Caleb Atwater to John Vaughan, January 13, 1830; 7 5/8" x 10"; Atwater, Caleb, 1778-1867
    Washington, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents samples of minerals to A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Godman's paper on extinct mammals, Jan. 15, 1830; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Isaac Lea, Z. Collins, R.Eglesfeld Griffith, and W.E.Horner. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.598. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 478 ff.
  - Report of committee on [Isaac] Hay's paper of a new species of extinct animals, Jan. 15, 1830; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Isaac Lea, Z. Collins and R.Eglesfeld Griffith. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.598.
  - Letter to J[ohn K.] Kane, secretary of the A.P.S., January 22, 1830; 7" x 8 3/4"; Wallenstein, Jules de, -1845
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership. Cf. Minutes, Jan. 15,1830.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, treasurer to the A.P.S., January 22, 1830; 7" x 8 3/4"; Wallenstein, Jules de, -1845
    Philadelphia, A.L. in 3d P. 1p. and end. Encloses his contribution as a member of the Society.
  - Report of committee on and article by Mease on plant fibers, Jan. 29, 1830; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: C.Pickering, Z. Collins, and Tho. C. James. 2p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.599.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 29, 1830; 10x8; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Rafn. 1p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Jan., 1830; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, L.S.: Van der Vinne. 1p. and end. In Dutch. Thanks for publications and forwards publications.
  - List of books presented to the American Philosophical Society by the Chevalier Frederick Adelung of St. Petersburg, February 5, 1830; 7 7/8" x 9 13/16"; Adelung, Friedrich von, 1768-1843
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 7, 1830; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Da Ponte, Lorenzo, 1749-1838
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Donates volumes.
  - Tho[ma]s Horsfield to Franklin Bache, February 9, 1830; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    Secretary of the A.P.S., [London], 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Tho[ma]s Horsfield to J[ohn] K. Kane, February 9, 1830; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, secretary of A.P.S., Feb. 11, 1830; 8" x 9 1/2"; Pougens, Charles de, 1755-1833
    Paris, L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Acknowledges receipt of his certificate of membership; mentions Benjamin and William Temple Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME128
  - James Brown to P[eter] S. DuPonceau, February 12, 1830; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; Brown, James, 1766-1835
    President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Thanks the Society for resolutions passed upon the death of his brother, the late Dr. Samuel Brown.
  - Report of the committee upon resolution to recommend the award of the Extra-Magellanic premium to John d'Homerque "for his valuable experiments on American Silk", February 19, 1830; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 6 pp. D.S.: Joseph] Hopkinson and four others. Hopkinson and four others. Refuse recommendation.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 21, 1830; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Winthrop, Thomas L. (Thomas Lindall), 1760-1841
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.,end.and add. Has received Transactions.
  - J[oel] R. Poinsett to John Vaughan, February 22, 1830; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Cincinnati, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Frank, the artist, who wishes to study the specimens of Mexican sculpture sent to Philadelphia by Poinsett.
  - Letter to P.S. Duponceau, president of the A.P.S., March 1, 1830; 7 1/2" x 9"; Jomard, M. (Edme-François), 1777-1862
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Acknowledges election to membership; sends some of his works.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, March 12, 1830; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of Scotland
    Edinburgh, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Donald Gregory. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., March 15, 1830; 14x8-1/2; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Yanoss. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, March 17, 1830; 7 3/4" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Book purchases in Paris. Coming sale of Lamarck's library. Has conferred with Michaux upon needs of A.P.S. library.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., March 18, 1830; 7 3/4" x 10"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding sixteen volumes purchased for A.P.S. Invoice for 26 francs included in the letter.
  - J[ohn] Marshall to J[ohn K. Kane, Richmond, March 26, 1830; 7 13/16" x 9 9/16"; Marshall, John
    1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March, 1830; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
  - W[illiam] H. Keating to John K. Kane, April 6, 1830; 8" x 10"; Keating, William Hypolitus, 1799-1840
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Encloses list of donations made to the A.P.S. by [Joel R.] Poinsett and himself.
  - Letter to Pierre S. DuPonceau, April 15, 1830; 10x8; Pereira de Azambuja, Jacob Frederico Torlade, 1788-1847
    Georgetown, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications. Questions.
  - Tho[ma]s Horsfield to John Vaughan, April 17, 1830; 7 1/2" x 9"; Horsfield, Thomas, 1773-1859
    Fairfield near Manchester, 4pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, April 20, 1830; 10x8; Griva, François
    Gênes, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Concerning donation.
  - Francis Lieber to J[ohn] Vaughan, April 23, 1830; 8" x 9 7/8"; Lieber, Francis, 1800-1872
    Secretary of A.P.S., Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns Creole Gospel. Hopes A.P.S. received vols. I and II of his work.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., April 24 and 26, 1830; 8 1/4" x 10 1/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Sends copy of invoice of books mentioned in letter of March 18. Sale of Lamarck's library. Purchase of five volumes (30 francs) for A.P.S.
  - W[illia]m B. Hodgson to J[ohn] K. Kane, April 25, 1830; 8" x 10"; Hodgson, William Brown, 1800-1871
    Secretary to the A.P.S., Washington, 2pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 26, 1830; 10x8; Welsh, Henry, 1800-1883
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 6, 1830; 10x8; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to [P] Pedersen, Philadelphia, May 8, 1830; 10x8; Bille, Steen, 1797-1883
    L.S.: Steen Bille, E. Holstein,Scheinheyder, 1p. and ad.,end. In Danish.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, Librarian of A.P.S., May 8, 1830; 8 1/4" x 10 1/4"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Paris, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Cooperation of Michaux regarding journals and bulletins. Question concerning payment of duties. Introducing Dr.Spencer.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 11, 1830; 10x8; Beasley, Reuben Grant
    Havre, L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards box from Warden.
  - Report of committee on Thomas Nuttall's paper on a new species of Sarracenia, May 20, 1830; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Zaccheus Collins, Solomon W.Conrad and Isaac Lea. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.602. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., IV, 49 ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 2, 1830; 10x8; New-York Historical Society
    New York, L.S.: J. Delafield. 1p. and add., end. Inquires if their donation has arrived.
  - W[illia]m Vaughan to John K. Kane, June 5, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Secretary of the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 11, 1830; 9-1/2x8; Poussin, Guillaume Tell, 1794-1876
    Washington, L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards map of Florida.
  - Letter to [ ], June 15, June 27, 1830; 8 1/2" x 10"; Reichel, J.
    St. Petersbourg, A.L.S. 3p. and end. In French. On procuring medals from the United States.
  - Report of committee on the memoir on light by Saunders, June 18, 1830; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: William Hambel, Robert Hare, and Solomon W. Conrad. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.602.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau, Philadelphia, June 25, 1830; 10-1/2x8; Barnet, I. Cox (Isaac Cox), d. 1833
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards Aldini's donation.
  - Letter to Robert Walsh, Philadelphia, June 26, 1830; 10x8; Mulledy, Thomas F.
    Georgetown College, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Forwards books for the APS library.
  - Letter to [Peter S.] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, June 28, 1830; 10x8; Aldini, Giovanni, 1762-1834
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. and add.,end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - W[illia]m Yarrell to the secretaries of the A.P.S., June 28, 1830; 7 5/16" 9 1/8"; Yarrell, William, 1784-1856
    London, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his diploma of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 30, 1830; 13x8-1/2; Abrahamson, J. N. B. v. (Joseph Nicolai Benjamin)